Guide to the United Polish Societies of Ambridge Records, 1930-1966 AIS.1979.05
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Polish Societies of Ambridge Records
1930-1966
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Polish Societies of Ambridge (Pa.)
AIS.1979.05
1.25 Linear Feet (1 box)
The records of the United Polish Societies of Ambridge, Pennsylvania, include correspondence, bylaws, delegates, reports, membership lists, programs, press releases, post cards, Christmas cards, and songs, 1930-1966.
Scope and Content Notes
The records of the United Polish Societies of Ambridge, Pennsylvania, include correspondence, bylaws, delegates, reports, membership lists, programs, press releases, post cards, Christmas cards, and songs, 1930-1966. Much of the material in this collection relates to musical groups (Kapela) belonging to the Society. The records also relate to committees and letters from Poland during World War II, including thank-you cards from Polish soldiers fighting in the war.
Note: Portions of this collection are in Polish.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the United Polish Societies of Ambridge, January 26, 1979.
Previous Citation
United Polish Societies of Ambridge Records, 1930-1966, AIS.1979.05, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
United Polish Societies of Ambridge, Records, 1930-1966, AIS 79:5, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Ethnic groups; Polish American fraternal organizations -- Pennsylvania -- Ambridge; Polish Americans -- Pennsylvania -- Ambridge -- Societies and clubs; Societies
- Correspondence, 1930-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, Consulate of the Republic of Poland, 1933-1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Kapela-Sprawozdania, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, Drum and Bugle Corps, 1938-1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, Fundusz Obrony Naradowej, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, Fundusz Ratunkowy, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, Dzien Polski, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Polish National Alliance Bylaws, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Delegates List, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Roznelisty do Towartzystw, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Sprawozdania Urzedukow, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Komitet Oswiaty, 1930-1940 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Kapela Uroczptosi Posuricenia Sztander, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Reports, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Reports, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Receipts, Kapela-Rachunki, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Committee Membership List, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Programs, 1937-1961 (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
- Press Releases, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Letters from Poland, August 1946 - December 1946 (Box 1, Folder 23-28)
- Letters from Poland, January 1947- December 1947 (Box 1, Folder 29-42)
- Letters from Poland, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 43-45)
- Letters from Poland, February, March, July, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 46-48)
- Letters from Poland, ca. 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Post Cards, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Miscellaneous letters, undated (Box 1, Folder 51-53)
- Letters from Overseas, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 54-56)
- Christmas Cards, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 57-59)
- Thank-you Cards, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Clippings/Songs, no date (Box 1, Folder 61)